# ALEX LING

# EDUCATION

09/2014 - 05/2018 New York, NY NEW YORK UNIVERSITY (3.816/4.0)

Gallatin School of Individualized Study

Individualized Major: "Visual Storytelling and

Deconstructing Narratives"

Minor: Business of Entertainment, Media, and

Technology (Stern School of Business)

**COURSES** 

Design I & II // Contemporary Visual Culture and the Politics of Images // Entertainment & Media Industries // Media,

Technology, and Society // How Art Works

**ACTIVITIES** 

Founder and President of Gallazine

**Emerging Leader Award** 

Dean's List

08/2016 - 12/2016 Shanghai, China **NEW YORK UNIVERSITY SHANGHAI** (4.0/4.0)

Study Abroad: General Curriculum and

Interactive Media Arts

**COURSES** 

Communications Lab // Projects in Western and Chinese Methods of Art // Chinese II

# **EXPERIENCE**

01/2017 - Present New York, NY

## AMINO APPS // Design Intern

// Design and illustrate app icons, mobile assets, and iOS and Android screenshots for app stores

// Social media rebrand of Instagram and Twitter, design ad campaigns, make graphics and animations for social media, mockup mobile UI designs

// Reach out to artists to feature fan content on Amino

02/2016 - 06/2016 New York, NY

# **VISIT.ORG** // Visual Editor Intern

// Curate, edit, and upload images to WordPress for organization pages

// Organize images and design promotional presentations

09/2015 - 11/2015 New York, NY

### THE HOLE // Gallery and Operations Intern

// Open and close gallery, greet visitors, answer questions about exhibitions, install and deinstall exhibitions, art handling, design exhibit postcards

02/2015 - 06/2015 New York, NY

### SCHOLASTIC // Art Dept Admin Assistant

// Invoice and record-keeping, contract editing, sample warehouse ordering

// Image and photo research, file conversion, assemble prototypes, create "child-like" drawings and handwriting for products

07/2013 - 08/2013 New York, NY

# THE MET // Education and Digital Media Intern

// Edit thumbnail images for new audio guides // Verify, organize, and tabulate content from 10+ audio guides with 100+ audio guide tour stops

// Create and lead group gallery tour and discussion

PHONE: (908) 399-5353 LOCATION: NY // NJ

## PROFILE

Hi! I'm Alex. I'm currently a senior at NYU's Gallatin School of Individualized Study where I'm pursuing an individualized major centering around design, art history, and marketing, specifically the ways to best visually communicate ideas and narratives. I'm also minoring in BEMT at NYU's Stern School of Business. I have professional experience in design, visual curation, and making creative content. In my free time, I'm usually found drawing comics and working on my UI/UX skills.

WEBSITE LINKEDIN PORTFOLIO GITHUB INSTAGRAM aswling.com /alexandraling @alexswling /aswling @aswling

### **SKILLS**

Photoshop
Illustrator
InDesign
Premiere
Audacity
HTML/CSS
JavaScript
InVision
Photography
PaintTool SAI



### **FAVE PROJECTS**

Skin Deep (2016)
FEED Magazine (2017)
Through the Bund (2016)
Zàijiàn (2016)
Homecoming (2017)
Of Mice and Men (2017)